<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Summary on Svtter's Blog</title><link>https://svtter.cn/en/categories/summary/</link><description>Recent content in Summary on Svtter's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:08:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://svtter.cn/en/categories/summary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2024 Q3 Summary</title><link>https://svtter.cn/en/p/2024-q3-summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:08:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://svtter.cn/en/p/2024-q3-summary/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a summary for July 2024 to September 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quarter passed quite quickly; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem long since the last review. There truly is a gap in intelligence between people; I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m a not-very-hardworking fool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When conducting a review, try not to modify the content of the journal as much as possible. Otherwise, it will be troublesome to trace back later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="life-life"&gt;Life #life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of my energy during this period has been focused on taking care of my pregnant wife. The child was born safely, and the mother is doing well and happy 😆. For friends preparing for pregnancy and childbirth, I recommend this book: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://u.jd.com/CaQxLPw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Pregnant with My Wife&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Pregnancy is quite challenging for both men and women. Influenced by hormones, emotions can often fluctuate easily, and the man needs to balance work and family well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financially, prepare sufficient funds and budget for family expenses in advance. If your job is not stable enough, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend rushing to have children. Although the old saying goes, &amp;ldquo;Start a family before establishing a career,&amp;rdquo; starting a family doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean having children immediately. During pregnancy, the emotional needs of the woman will be higher, so be mentally prepared. It&amp;rsquo;s best to seek advice from slightly older friends or relatives. Also, pay special attention to the location for childbirth. The ideal situation is to have your own independent family. Otherwise, you might have to deal with a series of complicated matters, which can be exhausting. Adding work pressure on top of that makes it even more difficult. In short, if conditions aren&amp;rsquo;t right, don&amp;rsquo;t have children; don&amp;rsquo;t make things hard for yourself. If you&amp;rsquo;re unhappy, your family will likely be unhappy too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;em&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://u.jd.com/C1q68Mr" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; but couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish it. Made a small profit in stocks and cashed out; couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up with the market trend anymore. In investment and financial management, too many people want to make quick money, so designing strategies directly aimed at quick profits can make money. Leverage is absolutely not advisable; it&amp;rsquo;s just used to deceive gamblers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how the friend who borrowed money to buy stocks a couple of days ago is doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="research-research"&gt;Research #Research
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although a new network was constructed, it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be transformed into a publishable paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="experiments-and-new-research"&gt;Experiments and New Research
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;New experiments verified that CRNN is still the best method in certain scenarios; formed an article specifically discussing CTC. However, it&amp;rsquo;s not yet at the level for publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried many multimodal approaches, different encoding methods, word embedding, and one-hot. Spent a lot of time learning about transformers.
Completed querynet, a new structure for solving multimodal problems. However, it still hasn&amp;rsquo;t solved the problem I proposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of mid-term progress, the content is insufficient. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve done many experiments now, relatively few can be solidified into theories, and the overall coherence is lacking. This is not very consistent with the original plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding submissions, just received feedback on the new paper SWR; the new paper has been rejected and is still in rebuttal. But overall, it&amp;rsquo;s still okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that the current research progress is fine, but there haven&amp;rsquo;t been significant achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="some-thoughts"&gt;Some Thoughts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If researching a field, spend time exploring, organizing materials, and increasing understanding of the industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organizing thoughts #thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tech-related-tech"&gt;Tech-related #Tech
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensively adopted functional programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deeply explored the React framework, understood &lt;code&gt;useState&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;useEffect&lt;/code&gt;, and fixed many bugs in the framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deeply explored react-router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="project-related-project"&gt;Project-related #project
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a relatively universal front-end and back-end underlying framework. Front-end based on React, back-end based on Django Ninja.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After so many years of development, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally solidified something. By using this framework, many problems brought by the native Django and React frameworks can be avoided. This is a kind of account for all these years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The framework still has many areas for improvement, with the biggest help being efficiency improvement. If there&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity, it will be open-sourced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="next-quarter"&gt;Next Quarter
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust SWR well, submit it, and strive to get one article accepted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a way forward for querynet and the new research problem proposed, respectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch meterhub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of completing the above, finish the projects at hand and then organize the graduation thesis.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>