<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Svtter's Blog</title><link>https://svtter.cn/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Svtter's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 10:53:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://svtter.cn/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Write Useless Comments</title><link>https://svtter.cn/p/how-to-write-useless-comments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 10:53:25 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://svtter.cn/p/how-to-write-useless-comments/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a peculiar trend among some reviewers: they seem to have a knack for crafting comments that could pass as a generic template for any manuscript. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they&amp;rsquo;ve mastered the art of writing feedback so vague it could be applied to any paper, leaving authors to decipher the cryptic messages and make revisions that might as well be written in the stars. Here&amp;rsquo;s a prime example of such an &amp;rsquo;evergreen&amp;rsquo; comment:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Comments to the Author
The manuscript presents a XX method for XX. The topic is relevant and has potential applications. However, there are some issues to be addressed. Here are the comments:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The authors shall improve the clarity and cohesion of the manuscript. There are quite a few grammatical errors and misleading phrasing that hinder the reader’s understanding. I recommend thorough proofreading and editing by a native English speaker or a professional editor to improve the overall readability.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Several technical terms are misused or poorly explained. This makes it challenging for readers, especially those unfamiliar with the topic, to grasp the underlying concepts. A more precise use of terminology and better definitions would enhance comprehension.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is crucial to highlight what distinguishes this approach from previous works and to clearly articulate the specific contributions to the existing body of knowledge. In addition, it would be better to include a comparative analysis with other established techniques would strengthen the argument for its effectiveness.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The reviewer could just change the &amp;lsquo;method&amp;rsquo; to any term in any article, and the author is left to revise their paper as if it&amp;rsquo;s a never-ending game of academic whack-a-mole.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If specific details were added to the above content, it would be completely different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Directly point out where the grammatical errors are.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identify the misused technical terms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide more specific issues in the context of the field.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s work together to improve the environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2024-Q1 Summary</title><link>https://svtter.cn/p/2024-q1-summary/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 11:00:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://svtter.cn/p/2024-q1-summary/</guid><description>&lt;p>第一季度过的如此之快！效率感觉不高，但实际上做的东西还可以。开心！&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="academic">Academic
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Paper-2 R-3 完成&lt;/li>
&lt;li>active learning, human in the loop, domain adaptation, meter 论文的阅读&lt;/li>
&lt;li>论文审稿&lt;/li>
&lt;li>meter related 老代码整理，数据整理&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="work">work
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>交付了两个项目&lt;/li>
&lt;li>可以公开的进展：meterhub&lt;/li>
&lt;li>一个 django 插件 &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/Svtter/django-login-email" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>django-email-login&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>一个用于 email 验证登录的工具&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>企业微信设立&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="在下一个季度要完成的事情">在下一个季度，要完成的事情
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>中期报告&lt;/li>
&lt;li>第二篇小论文中，第三篇小论文投出&lt;/li>
&lt;li>会议论文实验和论文写完投出&lt;/li>
&lt;li>meterhub&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MAYBE 找一个实习工作&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>